<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>category on Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/categories/category/</link>
    <description>Recent content in category on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 16:50:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/categories/category/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Genetics tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/geneticstools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 16:50:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/geneticstools/</guid>
      <description>Mus musculus 129S1 C57BL/6J BALB/cJ
Mouse genetics tools in brain vasculature system field NG2DsRedBAC: NG2DsRedBAC transgenic mice is suitable for pericyte and Artery SMC labeling in central nervous system. NG2DsRedBAC transgenic mice express an optimized red fluorescent protein variant (DsRed.T1) under the control of the mouse NG2 (Cspg4) promoter/enhancer and may be useful for fluorescent labeling of NG2 cells (oligodendrocyte progenitor cells) in the central nervous system and NG2-expressing cells in other organs, as well as for isolating NG2 cell populations via FACS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biochemistry tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/biochemistrytools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 17:16:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/biochemistrytools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our cells engage in protein production, and many of those proteins are enzymes responsible for the chemistry of life.      &amp;mdash; Randy Schekman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular biology tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/molecularbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 20:27:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/molecularbiology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress in science depends on new techniques, new discoveries and new ideas, probably in that order.      &amp;mdash; Sydney Brenner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/massspectrometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 13:24:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/massspectrometry/</guid>
      <description>LC-MS system MALDI system </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tissue clearing methods</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/clearingmethod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 12:23:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/clearingmethod/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This webinar will explain tissue clearing, how it functions, and the three main methods for making tissues transparent. Moreover, the advantages and limitations of various tissue cleansing methods.
PEGASOS (Using in our lab, recommended): PEGASOS version 1: Jing, Dian, et al. &amp;ldquo;Tissue clearing of both hard and soft tissue organs with the PEGASOS method.&amp;rdquo; Cell research 28.8 (2018): 803-818. [PDF | DOI Link]
TESOS system: Yi, Yating, et al. &amp;ldquo;Mapping of individual sensory nerve axons from digits to spinal cord with the Transparent Embedding Solvent System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/genomicsngs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 10:43:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/genomicsngs/</guid>
      <description>RNA-Seq KITS FOR RNA EXTRACTION Takara: Smart-Seq
SEQUENCING PLATFORM illumina; Huada Gene
ANALYSIS SOFTWARES QC
fastqc; multiqc; fastp
Reads Mapping
HISAT2: graph-based alignment of next generation sequencing reads to a population of genomes. (Manual)
STAR: The STAR software package maps large sets of high-throughput sequencing reads to a reference genome with high levels of accuracy and speed. (Manual)
TopHat: TopHat is a fast splice junction mapper for RNA-Seq reads. It aligns RNA-Seq reads to mammalian-sized genomes using the ultra high-throughput short read aligner Bowtie, and then analyzes the mapping results to identify splice junctions between exons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/imagingtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 10:43:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/imagingtools/</guid>
      <description>Confocal Microscopy Commercial Leica: Leica-SP8 (Archived Product Replaced by STELLARIS 5 &amp;amp; STELLARIS 8) ZEISS:
Two-Photon Microscopy Lab DIY Thorlabs: https://www.thorlabs.com/index.cfm
Ti:Sapphire Femtosecond Laser: From Thorlabs
AO (Adaptive optics) in 2PFM and for neurobiology
Commercial Olympus: FVMPE-RS
Leica: Leica-MP-4Tune
Scientifica: Multiphoton Imaging System
Ref labs: Ji Na lab, University of California, Berkeley
Janelia farm
In this talk, two-photon microscopy-which uses strong pulsed infrared lasers to produce detailed images inside biological samples-is introduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/programing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 08:30:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/programing/</guid>
      <description>R R-The R Project for Statistical Computing: https://www.r-project.org/
Rstudio: https://rstudio.com/
Books:
Python Python: https://www.python.org/
Spider IDE: https://www.spyder-ide.org/
Pycharm: https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/
Anaconda: https://www.anaconda.com/
Books:
Linux Redhat: https://www.redhat.com/en
Ubuntu: https://ubuntu.com/
CentOS: https://www.centos.org/
Forums: https://www.linux.org/
Books:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:16:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/research/</guid>
      <description>Brain vasculature system Our goal is to understand the principles underlying the formation of the brain vasculature system. Brain endothelial cells are one of the major components of brain vasculature system and involved in many kinds of brain vasculature disease, like AVM, CCM, HHT.
Brain metabolic system Metabolism is physiologically fundamental to a biological system. Understanding brain metabolism is critical for our comprehensive knowledge of brain function in health and disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications #: First author
✝: corresponding author
Lian Liu#, Linzhi Zou#, Kuan Li#, Hanqing Hou, Qun Hu, Shuang Liu, Jie Li, Chenmeng Song, Jiaofeng Chen, Shufeng Wang, Yangzhen Wang, Changri Li, Haibo Du, Jun-Liszt Li, Fangyi Chen, Zhigang Xu, Wenzhi Sun, Qianwen Sun, Wei Xiong✝ (2022) Template-independent genome editing in the Pcdh15av−3j mouse, a model of human DFNB23 nonsyndromic deafness. Cell Reports [DOI Link]
Samuel Lundt#, Nannan Zhang#, Jun-Liszt Li, Zhe Zhang, Xiaowan Wang, Ruisi Bao, Feng Cai, Wenzhi Sun, Woo-Ping Ge, Shinghua Ding✝ (2021) NAMPT deletion in project neurons induces bioenergetic stress and activates cell death and inflammatory pathways: Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow &amp;amp; Metabolism [PDF | DOI Link] Second author</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is Jun-Liszt Li. Currently, I am a graduate student in PKU-CIBR joint program of Peking University. My long-term goal is to discover and characterize basic mechanisms underlying brain aging and neuron growth. In addition, I working on Next-generation omics (scRNAseq; Spatial metabolomics) technology, next-generation microscopy (Lightsheet, Confocal, 2p), and next-generation gene therapy (AAV, promoter) in order to apply these technologies to solve specific problems.
Interest Areas Biological Question</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:10:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I live in Beijing, China. You can contact me through email or interact with me in twitter since I frequently check it.
Email Gmail: poppingjun7@gmail.com
Outlook: poppingjun@outlook.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
