<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>category on Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/categories/category/</link>
    <description>Recent content in category on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:16:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/categories/category/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:16:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/research/</guid>
      <description>Brain vasculature system Brain endothelial cells are major component ofbrain vasculature system and involved in many kinds of brain vasculaturedisease, like AVM, CCM, HHT.
Brain metabolic system Metabolism is physiologically fundamental to a biological system. Understanding brain metabolism is critical for our comprehensive knowledge of brain function in health and disease. In addition, brain is the most heterogeneous organ across whole body, in order to understand the metabolic basis, a detailed spatial metabolome atlas is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications #: First author
✝: corresponding author
Lian Liu#, Linzhi Zou#, Kuan Li#, Hanqing Hou, Qun Hu, Shuang Liu, Jie Li, Chenmeng Song, Jiaofeng Chen, Shufeng Wang, Yangzhen Wang, Changri Li, Haibo Du, Jun-Liszt Li, Fangyi Chen, Zhigang Xu, Wenzhi Sun, Qianwen Sun, Wei Xiong✝ (2022) Template-independent genome editing in the Pcdh15av−3j mouse, a model of human DFNB23 nonsyndromic deafness. Cell Reports Link
Samuel Lundt#, Nannan Zhang#, Jun-Liszt Li, Zhe Zhang, Xiaowan Wang, Ruisi Bao, Feng Cai, Wenzhi Sun, Woo-Ping Ge, Shinghua Ding✝ (2021) NAMPT deletion in project neurons induces bioenergetic stress and activates cell death and inflammatory pathways: Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow &amp;amp; Metabolism (PDF) Link Second author</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is Jun-Liszt Li. Currently, I am a graduate student in PKU-CIBR joint program of Peking University, working on Next-generation omics (scRNAseq; Spatial metabolomics) technology, and next-generation microscopy (Lightsheet, Confocal, 2p), in order to understand the fundamental basis of brain metabolism and brain vasculature system.
Interest Areas Brain vasculature system Brain metabolic system scRNAseq &amp;amp; Spatial transcriptome Spatial metabolomics AAV engineering Promoter engineering
Education Ph.D., Peking University, Beijing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:10:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I live in Beijing, China. You can contact me through email or interact with me in twitter since I frequently check it.
Email Gmail: poppingjun7@gmail.com
Outlook: poppingjun@outlook.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
