<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 16:50:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/resource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Genetics tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/geneticstools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 16:50:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/geneticstools/</guid>
      <description>Mus musculus 129S1 C57BL/6J BALB/cJ
Mouse genetics tools in brain vasculature system field NG2DsRedBAC: NG2DsRedBAC transgenic mice is suitable for pericyte and Artery SMC labeling in central nervous system. NG2DsRedBAC transgenic mice express an optimized red fluorescent protein variant (DsRed.T1) under the control of the mouse NG2 (Cspg4) promoter/enhancer and may be useful for fluorescent labeling of NG2 cells (oligodendrocyte progenitor cells) in the central nervous system and NG2-expressing cells in other organs, as well as for isolating NG2 cell populations via FACS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biochemistry tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/biochemistrytools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 17:16:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/biochemistrytools/</guid>
      <description>Vendor companies Abcam ThermoFisher R&amp;amp;D Systems BioRad Ref Labs Signaling pathway and basic science Zhijian-James Chen lab, UTSW David M. Sabatini lab, MIT Xiaodong Wang lab, UTSW, NIBS Feng Shao lab, NIBS Tool development Alice Ting lab, Stanford Ref. Protocols Bio-protocol Protocol Exchange </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular biology tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/molecularbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 20:27:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/molecularbiology/</guid>
      <description>Fluorescence Proteins -iRFP: miRFPnano670
RFPs: mRuby3, mCherry
GFPs: mGreenLantern, EGFP
BFPs: TagBFP2, TagBFP
Reference FPbase: FPbase is a moderated, user-editable fluorescent protein database designed by microscopists. Tissue/Cell type specific AAVs Brain organ specific: BR1
Liver specific:
Brain endothelial cell specific: AAV-BI30
Tissue/Cell type specific promoter Pan-neuron: hSyn
Kügler, S., E. Kilic, and M. Bähr. &amp;ldquo;Human synapsin 1 gene promoter confers highly neuron-specific long-term transgene expression from an adenoviral vector in the adult rat brain depending on the transduced area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/massspectrometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 13:24:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/massspectrometry/</guid>
      <description>LC-MS system MALDI system </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tissue clearing methods</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/clearingmethod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 12:23:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/clearingmethod/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This webinar will explain tissue clearing, how it functions, and the three main methods for making tissues transparent. Moreover, the advantages and limitations of various tissue cleansing methods.
PEGASOS (Using in our lab, recommended): PEGASOS version 1: Jing, Dian, et al. &amp;ldquo;Tissue clearing of both hard and soft tissue organs with the PEGASOS method.&amp;rdquo; Cell research 28.8 (2018): 803-818. [PDF | DOI Link]
TESOS system: Yi, Yating, et al. &amp;ldquo;Mapping of individual sensory nerve axons from digits to spinal cord with the Transparent Embedding Solvent System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/genomicsngs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 10:43:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/genomicsngs/</guid>
      <description>RNA-Seq KITS FOR RNA EXTRACTION Takara: Smart-Seq
SEQUENCING PLATFORM illumina; Huada Gene
ANALYSIS SOFTWARES QC
fastqc; multiqc; fastp
Reads Mapping
HISAT2: graph-based alignment of next generation sequencing reads to a population of genomes. (Manual)
STAR: The STAR software package maps large sets of high-throughput sequencing reads to a reference genome with high levels of accuracy and speed. (Manual)
TopHat: TopHat is a fast splice junction mapper for RNA-Seq reads. It aligns RNA-Seq reads to mammalian-sized genomes using the ultra high-throughput short read aligner Bowtie, and then analyzes the mapping results to identify splice junctions between exons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging tools</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/imagingtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 10:43:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/imagingtools/</guid>
      <description>Confocal Microscopy Commercial Leica: Leica-SP8 (Archived Product Replaced by STELLARIS 5 &amp;amp; STELLARIS 8) ZEISS:
Two-Photon Microscopy Lab DIY Thorlabs: https://www.thorlabs.com/index.cfm
Ti:Sapphire Femtosecond Laser: From Thorlabs
AO (Adaptive optics) in 2PFM and for neurobiology
Commercial Olympus: FVMPE-RS
Leica: Leica-MP-4Tune
Scientifica: Multiphoton Imaging System
Ref labs: Ji Na lab, University of California, Berkeley
Janelia farm
In this talk, two-photon microscopy-which uses strong pulsed infrared lasers to produce detailed images inside biological samples-is introduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/programing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 08:30:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/programing/</guid>
      <description>R R-The R Project for Statistical Computing: https://www.r-project.org/
Rstudio: https://rstudio.com/
Books:
Python Python: https://www.python.org/
Spider IDE: https://www.spyder-ide.org/
Pycharm: https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/
Anaconda: https://www.anaconda.com/
Books:
Linux Redhat: https://www.redhat.com/en
Ubuntu: https://ubuntu.com/
CentOS: https://www.centos.org/
Forums: https://www.linux.org/
Books:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
