<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Draw connecting routes on map with R</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2022/08/15/index.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2022/08/15/index.en-us/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a background of a world map. Fortunately, the maps library includes a world shape. It is simple to plot using the map() function, which takes a few arguments for customization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the brain connectivity atlas: reconstruction and revision of large-scale microscopic brain atlas</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2020/04/28/tailoring-the-brain-connectivity-atlas-reconstruction-and-revision-of-large-scale-microscopic-brain-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2020/04/28/tailoring-the-brain-connectivity-atlas-reconstruction-and-revision-of-large-scale-microscopic-brain-atlas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In complex biological systems, it is often the structure of the object of study that determines its function. This is also true for neural network systems. In order to understand the complexity of the structure of animal brain networks and their potential functions, brain mapping is one of the important goals in the current brain project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The origin and function of brain oscillation</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2019/06/14/the-origin-and-function-of-brain-oscillation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2019/06/14/the-origin-and-function-of-brain-oscillation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since German neurobiologist Hans Berger first documented spontaneous rhythmic fluctuations in the human electroencephalogram. Many scholars become captivated by this phenomena and attempt to unravel its secret. This periodic change in the brain is known as brain oscillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R plot 2d density</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2019/05/01/r-plot-2d-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2019/05/01/r-plot-2d-density/</guid>
      <description>a 2d density plot using ggplot2If you have a large number of points, a 2d density plot is helpful for examining the connection between 2 numerical variables.
It divides the plot area into several little fragments to prevent overlapping (as in the scatterplot next to it) and shows the number of points in each fragment.
Different kinds of 2D density graphs exist. Everyone has the appropriate ggplot2 function. All of them are discussed in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary report of attending SEU-Allen NRA International Workshop</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2018/09/25/index.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2018/09/25/index.en-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary focus of this meeting is to bring together expert neuroanatomists and computer scientists from different organizations to discuss cutting-edge research and applications on brain-wide reconstructions of neuron morphologies from whole-brain imaging datasets. Specifically, discussions will focus on effective data management, reconstruction workflows and common data quality and format standards for data sharing and reuse of manual, semi-automatic, and fully automatic neuron reconstructions at different organizations and at different resolution scales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
