<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:16:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:16:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/research/</guid>
      <description>Brain vasculature system Brain endothelial cells are major component ofbrain vasculature system and involved in many kinds of brain vasculaturedisease, like AVM, CCM, HHT.
Brain metabolic system Metabolism is physiologically fundamental to a biological system. Understanding brain metabolism is critical for our comprehensive knowledge of brain function in health and disease. In addition, brain is the most heterogeneous organ across whole body, in order to understand the metabolic basis, a detailed spatial metabolome atlas is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications #: First author
✝: corresponding author
Lian Liu#, Linzhi Zou#, Kuan Li#, Hanqing Hou, Qun Hu, Shuang Liu, Jie Li, Chenmeng Song, Jiaofeng Chen, Shufeng Wang, Yangzhen Wang, Changri Li, Haibo Du, Jun-Liszt Li, Fangyi Chen, Zhigang Xu, Wenzhi Sun, Qianwen Sun, Wei Xiong✝ (2022) Template-independent genome editing in the Pcdh15av−3j mouse, a model of human DFNB23 nonsyndromic deafness. Cell Reports Link
Samuel Lundt#, Nannan Zhang#, Jun-Liszt Li, Zhe Zhang, Xiaowan Wang, Ruisi Bao, Feng Cai, Wenzhi Sun, Woo-Ping Ge, Shinghua Ding✝ (2021) NAMPT deletion in project neurons induces bioenergetic stress and activates cell death and inflammatory pathways: Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow &amp;amp; Metabolism (PDF) Link Second author</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is Jun-Liszt Li. Currently, I am a graduate student in PKU-CIBR joint program of Peking University, working on Next-generation omics (scRNAseq; Spatial metabolomics) technology, and next-generation microscopy (Lightsheet, Confocal, 2p), in order to understand the fundamental basis of brain metabolism and brain vasculature system.
Interest Areas Brain vasculature system Brain metabolic system scRNAseq &amp;amp; Spatial transcriptome Spatial metabolomics AAV engineering Promoter engineering
Education Ph.D., Peking University, Beijing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:10:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I live in Beijing, China. You can contact me through email or interact with me in twitter since I frequently check it.
Email Gmail: poppingjun7@gmail.com
Outlook: poppingjun@outlook.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draw connecting routes on map with R</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2022/08/15/index.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2022/08/15/index.en-us/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by drawing a world map backgroud. Fortunately, the world shape is provided by the maps library. It can easily be plotted using the map() function that accepts a few arguments for customization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大脑连接图谱的“裁缝” ：大规模微观脑图谱的重建与修正</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2020/04/28/%E5%A4%A7%E8%84%91%E8%BF%9E%E6%8E%A5%E5%9B%BE%E8%B0%B1%E7%9A%84%E8%A3%81%E7%BC%9D-%E5%A4%A7%E8%A7%84%E6%A8%A1%E5%BE%AE%E8%A7%82%E8%84%91%E5%9B%BE%E8%B0%B1%E7%9A%84%E9%87%8D%E5%BB%BA%E4%B8%8E%E4%BF%AE%E6%AD%A3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2020/04/28/%E5%A4%A7%E8%84%91%E8%BF%9E%E6%8E%A5%E5%9B%BE%E8%B0%B1%E7%9A%84%E8%A3%81%E7%BC%9D-%E5%A4%A7%E8%A7%84%E6%A8%A1%E5%BE%AE%E8%A7%82%E8%84%91%E5%9B%BE%E8%B0%B1%E7%9A%84%E9%87%8D%E5%BB%BA%E4%B8%8E%E4%BF%AE%E6%AD%A3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在复杂生物系统里，往往研究对象的结构决定着其功能。神经网络系统亦是如此。为了理解动物大脑网络结构的复杂性及其潜在的功能，在目前的大脑计划中，脑图谱的绘制是重要的目标之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin and function of brain oscillation</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2019/06/14/the-origin-and-function-of-brain-oscillation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2019/06/14/the-origin-and-function-of-brain-oscillation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since neurobiologist Hans Berger from German first reported spontaneous rhythmic variations in the human electroencephalogram [Berger 1929]. Many researchers become fascinated with this phenomenon and try to uncover its mystery. This rhythmic variations in brain is generally referred to brain oscillation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R plot 2d pixel</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2019/05/01/r-plot-2d-pixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2019/05/01/r-plot-2d-pixel/</guid>
      <description>2d density plot with ggplot2A 2d density plot is useful to study the relationship between 2 numeric variables if you have a huge number of points.
To avoid overlapping (as in the scatterplot beside), it divides the plot area in a multitude of small fragment and represents the number of points in this fragment.
There are several types of 2d density plots. Each has its proper ggplot2 function. This post describes all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
