<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:16:05 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:16:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/photos/</guid>
      <description>Prague City &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;Art works By Jun-Liszt Li&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;In IOCB lab, Prague 2024 Christmas party in IOCB&#xA;2024 Christmas party in prague&#xA;lab dinner, 2024&#xA;lab dinner, 09/2024&#xA;lab lunch with MIT professor Regina Barzilay, 09/2024&#xA;lab dinner with Harvard professor Liron Bar-Peled (also lab alumni), 2025&#xA;lab BBQ, 2025&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;European Life style European cities In Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 04/2025&#xA;With Scientific Giants In Peking University, Beijing, China &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutrient sensing mTORC1 pathway</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/nutrient_sensing_mtorc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/nutrient_sensing_mtorc1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nutrient sensing is a fundamental biological process that enables organisms to adapt to their environment by regulating cell growth and metabolism in response to nutrient availability. mTOR signaling pathway is evolved to be able to sense environmental cues and coordinates cellular growth, we are focusing the question: How does mTOR sense nutritional cues and coordinates cellular growth ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain vasculature system</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/brain_vas_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/brain_vas_system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to understand the principles underlying the formation of the brain vasculature system. Brain endothelial cells (ECs) are one of the major components of brain vasculature system and involved in many kinds of genetic diseases and neuroninflammation related diseases, like bAVM, CCM, HHT, IA (Intracranial aneurysm), multiple sclerosis (MS) and stroke. We are developing and applying cutting edge technologies to interrogate the signal transduction pathways that involved in disease progression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular engineering</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/molecular_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/molecular_engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Synthetic protein structures and functions can now be designed entirely on a computer or produced through directed evolution in the laboratory. AAV capsid engineering is based on protein engineering, genetically encoded ion and metabolite sensors can be developed through protein engineering. We leverage this approach to create a next-generation platform for the study of brain vasculature system and brain metabolic system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protocol for tissue clearing and lightsheet imaging</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2023/04/11/protocol-for-tissue-clearing-and-lightsheet-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2023/04/11/protocol-for-tissue-clearing-and-lightsheet-imaging/</guid>
      <description>1. Tissue clearing PEGASOS tissue clearing technique, developed by the Zhao lab, enables the simultaneous clearing of both soft and hard tissues, making it suitable for 3D fluorescence imaging of whole organs. In our study, we applied the PEGASOS protocol to clear whole-brain samples from double-transgenic mice (Tek-Cre; Ai47) in which endothelial cells were labeled with a fluorescent reporter. This was done in preparation for subsequent 3D whole-organ imaging using light-sheet microscopy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brain metabolic system</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/brain_metabolome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/researchs/brain_metabolome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metabolism is physiologically fundamental to a biological system. Understanding brain metabolism is critical for our comprehensive knowledge of brain function in health and disease. In addition, brain is the most heterogeneous organ across whole body, in order to understand the metabolic basis, a detailed spatial metabolome atlas is needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protocol for calcium imaging of free-moving mice</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2022/12/22/protocol-for-calcium-imaging-of-free-moving-mice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2022/12/22/protocol-for-calcium-imaging-of-free-moving-mice/</guid>
      <description>1. Cranial window surgery Chronic cranial window implantation was performed following a standard protocol with the following specific steps for two-photon microscopy. Mice were anesthetized with isoflurane (induction 4%, maintenance 2%) and secured in a stereotaxic frame.&#xA;The scalp was incised and retracted to fully expose the skull, which was then cleaned by removing all overlying periosteum and fascia using a scalpel blade. Shallow, parallel scratches were made on the skull surface to enhance the adhesion of the subsequent adhesive layer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SleepyBoy</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/sleepyman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:50:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/sleepyman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SleepyBoy is a integrated app for automatic sleep staging analysis and visualization of EEG-EMG data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MetaBrain Explorer (Spatial Multi-omics Brain Explorer)</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/metabrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 09:46:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/metabrain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A online interactive website for browsing multi-omics data of mouse brain, which including brain cell type specific RNA-seq, sc-RNAseq, sc-ATACseq, brain spatial transcriptome, brain spatial metabolome, brain cell type specific proteome. Detailed gene information, protein domain, related publications are included.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VasCode system</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/minibend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:48:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/minibend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The VasCode system aims to integrate next-generation sequencing technologies such as whole-exome sequencing and CNV sequencing to identify potential disease-causing gene mutations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SpatialMeta (Online MALDI data analysis server)</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/spatialmeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 10:40:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/tooldevelopment/spatialmeta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A online interactive website for analyzing MALDI and spatial metabolomics/proteomics data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cellular Metabolism and Signaling</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/cellularmetabolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 20:14:35 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/cellularmetabolism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our cells engage in protein production, and many of those proteins are enzymes responsible for the chemistry of life.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Randy Schekman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neurobiology</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/neurobiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 20:14:35 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/neurobiology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although synapses differ in properties, all synapses operate by the same principle.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Sir Bernard Katz&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetics</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/geneticstools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 16:50:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/geneticstools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Progress in science depends on new techniques, new discoveries and new ideas, probably in that order.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Sydney Brenner&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/biochemistrytools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 17:16:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/biochemistrytools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our cells engage in protein production, and many of those proteins are enzymes responsible for the chemistry of life.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Randy Schekman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Biology</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/molecularbiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 20:27:51 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/molecularbiology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I cannot create, I do not understand.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Richard P. Feynman&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/massspectrometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 13:24:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/massspectrometry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Atoms are not indivisible, for negatively electrified particles can be torn from them by the action of electrical forces.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Sir J.J. Thomson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Biology</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/structure_bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 13:24:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/structure_bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My own prejudices are exactly the opposite of the functionalists&amp;rsquo;: &amp;ldquo;If you want to understand function, study structure&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Francis Crick&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tissue engineering methods</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/clearingmethod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 12:23:57 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/clearingmethod/</guid>
      <description>Tissue clearing methods Introduction This webinar will explain tissue clearing, how it functions, and the three main methods for making tissues transparent. Moreover, the advantages and limitations of various tissue cleansing methods.&#xA;Organic solvent-based tissue clearing PEGASOS (Using in our lab, recommended): PEGASOS version 1：Polyethylene glycol(PEG) Associated Solvent System&#xA;Jing, Dian, et al. &amp;ldquo;Tissue clearing of both hard and soft tissue organs with the PEGASOS method.&amp;rdquo; Cell research 28.8 (2018): 803-818.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genomics and Sequencing</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/genomicsngs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 10:43:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/genomicsngs/</guid>
      <description>RNA-Seq KITS FOR RNA EXTRACTION Takara: Smart-Seq&#xA;SEQUENCING PLATFORM illumina; Huada Gene&#xA;ANALYSIS SOFTWARES QC:&#xA;fastqc: FastQC aims to provide a simple way to do some quality control checks on raw sequence data coming from high throughput sequencing pipelines. It provides a modular set of analyses which you can use to give a quick impression of whether your data has any problems of which you should be aware before doing any further analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microscopic Imaging</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/imagingtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 10:43:49 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/imagingtools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Believing is seeing and seeing is believing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&amp;mdash; Tom Hanks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming &amp; Coding</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/resource/programing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 08:30:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/resource/programing/</guid>
      <description>R R-The R Project for Statistical Computing: https://www.r-project.org/&#xA;Rstudio: Rstudio Workbench is an integrated development environment for R and Python, with a console, syntax-highlighting editor that supports direct code execution, and tools for plotting, history, debugging and workspace management.&#xA;RShiny: Shiny is an R package that makes it easy to build interactive web apps straight from R. You can host standalone apps on a webpage or embed them in R Markdown documents or build dashboards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications #: First author&#xA;✝: corresponding author&#xA;¶: me&#xA;Jun-Liszt Li#, Zhanying Bi#, Xingjun Chen#, Tianyue Ming, Baoshan Qiu, Fengzhi Li, Ziyan Feng, Daosheng Ai, Tingting Zhang, Jiayu Wang, Shuai Lin, Yiping Lu, Hu Zhao, Zhanjing Wang, Juan Huang, Fei Zhao, Hu Zhao, Yilong Wang, Wenzhi Sun✝, Woo-ping Ge✝. “rAAV-miniBEND: A targeted vector for brain endothelial cell gene delivery and cerebrovascular malformation modeling” BioRxiv (15/06/2025) [DOI Link] Nature Biomedical Engineering (29/10/2025) [DOI Link] First author</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is Jun-Liszt Li. Currently, I am a postdoc researcher in David M. Sabatini lab. Before that, I was a graduate student in PKU-CIBR joint program of Peking University. My long-term goal is to discover and characterize basic mechanisms underlying brain aging and neuron growth. In addition, I worked on next-generation gene delivery tools (AAV, promoter) in order to apply these technologies to explore animal physiology and address specific problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:10:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I live in Prague, Czech Republic. You can contact me through email or interact with me in twitter/X(@poppingjun) since I frequently check it.&#xA;Email Gmail: poppingjun7@gmail.com&#xA;Outlook: poppingjun@outlook.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Draw connecting routes on map with R</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2022/08/15/index.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2022/08/15/index.en-us/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a background of a world map. Fortunately, the maps library includes a world shape. It is simple to plot using the map() function, which takes a few arguments for customization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the brain connectivity atlas: reconstruction and revision of large-scale microscopic brain atlas</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2020/04/28/tailoring-the-brain-connectivity-atlas-reconstruction-and-revision-of-large-scale-microscopic-brain-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2020/04/28/tailoring-the-brain-connectivity-atlas-reconstruction-and-revision-of-large-scale-microscopic-brain-atlas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In complex biological systems, it is often the structure of the object of study that determines its function. This is also true for neural network systems. In order to understand the complexity of the structure of animal brain networks and their potential functions, brain mapping is one of the important goals in the current brain project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The origin and function of brain oscillation</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2019/06/14/the-origin-and-function-of-brain-oscillation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2019/06/14/the-origin-and-function-of-brain-oscillation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since German neurobiologist Hans Berger first documented spontaneous rhythmic fluctuations in the human electroencephalogram. Many scholars become captivated by this phenomena and attempt to unravel its secret. This periodic change in the brain is known as brain oscillation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R plot 2d density</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2019/05/01/r-plot-2d-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2019/05/01/r-plot-2d-density/</guid>
      <description>a 2d density plot using ggplot2&#xD;If you have a large number of points, a 2d density plot is helpful for examining the connection between 2 numerical variables.&#xA;It divides the plot area into several little fragments to prevent overlapping (as in the scatterplot next to it) and shows the number of points in each fragment.&#xA;Different kinds of 2D density graphs exist. Everyone has the appropriate ggplot2 function. All of them are discussed in this post.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary report of attending SEU-Allen NRA International Workshop</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/2018/09/25/index.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/2018/09/25/index.en-us/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary focus of this meeting is to bring together expert neuroanatomists and computer scientists from different organizations to discuss cutting-edge research and applications on brain-wide reconstructions of neuron morphologies from whole-brain imaging datasets. Specifically, discussions will focus on effective data management, reconstruction workflows and common data quality and format standards for data sharing and reuse of manual, semi-automatic, and fully automatic neuron reconstructions at different organizations and at different resolution scales.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
