<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Jun-Liszt Li</title>
    <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Jun-Liszt Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:16:05 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leoj.xyz/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 15:16:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/photos/</guid>
      <description>Prague City &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;Art works By Jun-Liszt Li&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;In IOCB lab, Prague 2024 Christmas party in IOCB&#xA;2024 Christmas party in prague&#xA;lab dinner, 2024&#xA;lab dinner, 09/2024&#xA;lab lunch with MIT professor Regina Barzilay, 09/2024&#xA;lab dinner with Harvard professor Liron Bar-Peled (also lab alumni), 2025&#xA;lab BBQ, 2025&#xA;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&#xA;European Life style In Jardin des Tuileries, Paris, France, 11/2025&#xA;European cities In Frankfurt am Main, Germany, 04/2025</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications #: First author&#xA;✝: corresponding author&#xA;¶: me&#xA;Jun-Liszt Li# ¶, Zhanying Bi#, Xingjun Chen#, Tianyue Ming, Baoshan Qiu, Fengzhi Li, Ziyan Feng, Daosheng Ai, Tingting Zhang, Jiayu Wang, Shuai Lin, Yiping Lu, Hu Zhao, Zhanjing Wang, Juan Huang, Fei Zhao, Hu Zhao, Yilong Wang, Wenzhi Sun✝, Woo-ping Ge✝. “A targeted vector for brain endothelial cell gene delivery and cerebrovascular malformation modeling.” Nature Biomedical Engineering (29/10/2025) [PDF | PMID: 41162685 | DOI Link] First author</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:15:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Personal Statement Hello, My name is Jun-Liszt Li. I am currently working as a postdoc researcher in David M. Sabatini lab (IOCB Boston and IOCB Prague), a leading center for nutrient sensing and growth control research. My research focus is to understand the upstream logic of mTORC1 nutrient sensing pathway. At the Sabatini Lab, I have been fortunate to receive rigorous training in biochemistry and mechanistic cell biology. This experience not only refined my experimental precision but also shaped the way I think about scientific questions — emphasizing clarity, reproducibility, and the pursuit of fundamental molecular principles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 15:10:15 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leoj.xyz/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I live in Prague, Czech Republic — one of the most beautiful cities in Europe and the world!🏰. Prague is also a city that continues to inspire us with its rich history and beautiful architecture.&#xA;For general inquiries, collaboration opportunities, or technical support, please reach out to me through email or interact with me in twitter/X(@poppingjun).&#xA;We value your input and we look forward to connecting with you!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
